this this is for side
commonly translated as grasp
an attachment or assumptions do you like
to say will be done for the one I'm
interested did to a button so assumption
to use recommended translators grasping
you've used yeah yeah probably grasping
is kind of eating it implies that you
are aware of what you're grasping
towards but you going towards things
it's ordered on the basis of false
assumption or assumption in regard to
those things that's where you're already
reaching out because you assume that you
can reach out so when it comes to views
assumption to views well D to Perdana
means basically that you're already not
even aware that you're acting out of
your views which means you need to undo
your lack of awareness to become aware
that you've been assuming the standpoint
off of you it's not like oh I must stop
holding fixed views everything as if it
is a method of choice because as the
Buddha said in there to the well that
view is fixed then when that man man
said oh my view is that no view is
pleasing to me which is what usually
people chant into temples and say don't
hold to fix views and then they will say
well not hold no view is pleasing to me
well that's surely pleasing to you and
then Spence oh it is isn't it
so I don't hold to fix views is your
fixed position you can't just decide to
let go of the views and that's what I
mean oopah donna is not like grasping cuz
oopah donna is not like grasping cuz
grasping yeah I I'm not gonna grasp for
this and people think okay so that's how
I'm doing my ipod on I know you'll do
your Hoopa don't know where you see it
see you can only take something at face
value until you know the real value you
can only take something at the for
granted a nature of something for
granted until you have understood that
nature then even if it were the same as
to what you assumed you won't be
assuming it because you know it so
assumption and knowledge are mutually
exclusive absence of knowledge means
presence of assumption presence of
knowledge means absence of assumption
dark and light pencil the similar story
that would give and that's literally
what assumption means even in Greek are
somatic take for granted take it the
face value without knowing what I think
it and then you does also your whole
actual existence I am and this is mine
these things are for me that's already
on the basis of that assumption that
these things are like that and if you
wonder whether you assume things well
ask yourself the Buddha said the one who
is free from assumption is free from
suffering am I free from suffering no
means the assumptions are there but you
can't find them as the objects of your
attention because your attention is
already rooted in that assumed basis and
that's what the views are that's what
the view is the most blame war do you
think as the Buddha said wrong view cuz
round view everything is well gonna be
tainted by that wrongness
of that view even if you're doing right
things so an example of well an example
of wrong view what many view sensuality
with you have sense itself art avada
obviously yeah whether there's focus is
assumption of to sensuality assumptions
views assumption to a virtual duty and
assumption to yeah yeah they all share
the same nature mm-hmm it's just a
different extents but it's the same
principle of you acting out of a
standpoint that's based on ignorance
it's based on your active ignoring of it
so that's why it takes that effort to
stop in orient and undo and do basically
your own lack of lack of knowledge in
regard to it and that's how the
assumption falls off that's how you stop
fueling the assumption you can just make
a choice to not assume because your
choice is already a result of your
assumption of your view of
your existence is of your view of what
you are while your sense of self is what
the ownership is that's what we like
encourage people to question yourself
because that's how it's not questioning
what you took for granted I remember in
my own case like I was doing walking
meditation and sort of contemplating
consciousness and five aggregates and
then it dawned on me I'm using all these
terms and designations like I say whole
consciousness and it's like this and so
that but without what it is what is it
that consciousness in itself the warden
I'm using I'm clearly designating
something what am i referring to so
realize that even terminology I was
using for myself I didn't have clarity
in regard to it so how can then that
unclear terminology result in clarity of
wisdom of that which precedes the
terminology that you try to designate
with those very terms so then instead of
trying to figure out what consciousness
is and what's most pleasing sort of
setup for what I think consciousness is
I thought what wait a minute I don't you
just say consciousness consciousness and
see at least approximately what am i
referring to right here right now in my
experience while I'm doing this were
communication when I say consciousness
and then they realize you people
including myself at a time using oh look
matter form consciousness feeling
intentions and then you build your
practice on top of it but wait a minute
what does those terms at a very basic
level at the face value what do they
mean in your ears I have no idea I have
a vague notion of the meaning and I
ignored that it's vague and then I carry
on building up a pleasing structure they
will result in magical product of
enlightenment but there is it's that's
one univita kept talking about undoing
the wrong views not like overdoing or
doing the top of them until you climb
onto the right view know right view is
by abandoning the wrong views I'm doing
the doing of wrong views it's another
way of saying abandon the wrong views
not abandon by outrunning them but
abandon by withdrawing yourself from the
wrongness out there
so that's why we need you you take all
this like I was taking feeling feeling
feeling whatever it is I was taking for
granted that whatever ambiguous vague
knowledge of feeling I had I took it for
granted that that's what feeling is
there's no that's where the problem is
not because I don't find out what the
feeling is
but because any movement in regard to
feeling that I can do it's done on the
basis of me having taken it for granted
already imply that that's what the
feeling is but that's not what the
feeling is how do I know that well
because I'm not free from suffering as
the Buddha said if you were to truly
understand the nature of feeling or any
aggregate you will be free from any
taking up for granted any assumption any
craving any suffering so that to me it's
about undoing and that's a view I Gucci
loosely was unaware that I was holding a
view that I knew what the aggregates are
when I was thinking about them and on
top of the view then I was trying to
practice the Dharma of understanding
what the aggregates were but once I
realized it is the opposite direction
from whether you are going with it so
he'll you practice the Dhamma but by
undoing what you think these views are
that's why everybody starts with a state
of total China and the way to stop being
a protrusion is to undo the aspects of
your experience that are maintaining you
as a petitioner not to kind of as I said
climb on top and reach some pinnacle
whereby you suddenly become a sotapanna
you become a soda burner by undoing the
doing of petitioner there's so much you
saying you assume it begin in this place
of purity
yeah and we go about our lives in it
exactly so you come across the Buddhist
teaching it makes sense to a degree and
you don't question that but then you
just try to build on top of it but
instead of building on top of it you
start questioning back to yourself wait
a minute okay no I've no doubt I'm not
doubting I'm not denying that this suit
that makes sense but instead of now
taking for granted that that's what the
Buddha also meant by that Souter let me
then change or rather
revise and see how
much it makes sense because by the end
of this Sutra people who understood it
became arahant so released sorta bonus a
marathon or release a soda ban and no
which means the degree of that suit the
making sense to me is not sufficient so
instead of building on top of that
degree in a direction of evolving the
sense let me undo what I think the
suitor is more and more until I get to
know what the suit is and you undo it by
the way I said so the suit that talks
about the foreground elements I have a
thought and concept of four Great
elements if that were truly what four
Great elements were our I would be free
from suffering or at least that would be
a sotapanna so when I think about the
four Great elements that's not what the
four Great elements up or rather I'm
thinking about the four Great elements
affected with ignorance assumption
craving and everything else which is why
I think I can think about the four Great
elements but at the same time not be
another hunt where I can think about the
five aggregates objectively without
padana but I'm not in our hunt that's a
contradiction in terms
if you can think about it objectively
you'll be free from suffering and you
know you're not free from suffering is
us you must you mustn't keep taking for
granted what you think objective
thinking is because you have a measure
of suffering that should be reducing the
more of your I mean I say objective I
mean more aligned with the nature of how
the aggregates actually are impermanent
unsatisfactory cannot be a base of
ownership so that's when the suitors
when when monks we won't understand
something you'd basically say that love
like feeling feeling what is feeling so
not like let me think about and develop
a concept of feeling but feeling feeling
so you designate it twice presently like
right here right now feeling I'm feeling
I'm feeling what is this feeling that
I'm feeling that I'm designating with my
verbal utterance with my thoughts what
am i referring to basically right here
right now how I'm referring this ooh yes
but all these concepts that I'm
providing now as an answer they are
secondary to the very direction
that I designated by saying feeling
feeling what am I feeling now because it
already implies that something's being
felt so now I'm asking what is being
felt while it is being felt so it forces
you to go against the grain up the
stream that's where it's unpleasant so
ambiguous opaque so dense so obtuse
because the attention everything goes
down with the grain and that's why the
yan is someone a seeker eyes deep like
the counterpart of Iona so with the
grain Yanis is basically back to the boom of
Yanis is basically back to the boom of
their grain and all of those types of
assumptions are basically views
fundamentally you think you have a view
that you are that you are your own that
you are your own master self controller
that's why you think things belong to
you and that you see view cannot add
anything to the aggregates nor can take
anything away from the actual aggregate
it can only confuse the order and put
first at which a second so in this sense
your sense of self I am
he's just so gratuitous assumed that is
seen as an independent entity that owns
things the chooses yes and says no but
once you realize that that's the wrong
order that it's not that you own things
because you are it's you are because you
keep maintaining the ownership of things
that's over said the possessions
determine you like that King would not
have been known as a king he wouldn't
have been a king without having the
possessions of a king he's not a king he
defines you so your body you stay all
these are possessions and that's why you
are that's why you have sense of self so
you don't deny the sense of self but you
are protein by seeing that it's not the
owner it's the result of ownership and
you will approach it when you see that
there gratuitous assumed ownership of these
gratuitous assumed ownership of these
things cannot beyond because they have a
reason on their own and it's only
because they persist on their own you
can maintain your gratuitous taking
interface values or this presented
itself for me with us I must be thus I
am thus this is mine you're not
analyzing things or breaking them into
parts to deny their reality
no you accept the reality because that's
the only way you can remove the
ownership of it you trying to break
things into party sake they see they're
not really real cause atoms and
electrons are constantly changing that's
you now obscuring your ownership to
denying the existence of things a is a
feeling his feeling perceptions
perception things are things phenomena phenomena
things are things phenomena phenomena
the woolum ever said or in the scene
there is no scene no he said in the
scene there is just the scene in the
reason there is just a reason there was
never a problem why would you then D go
and analyze that which has a reason what
is it made of failing to see that
doesn't matter the amount of parts you
discerned the functional arrangement of
that phenomena the big gives the context
to the part is still very real which is
what enables you to look at different
parts without losing the sight of the
thing that is being comprised by those
parts you can see that the dependence of
course the parts of within the context
of the thing which is what the thing is
you denying the existence of the thing
by saying it's made out of part it's
basically failing to see that each part
then is an individual thing as well so
then you just denying the existence away
because there is B C feelings are not
real because there are perceptions it's
a complete a magical assumption that
these things somehow relate or did they
cancel each other out so feeling is not
real because it's just hormones and
chemicals and sensations running through
your body
so would you know hormones and
cessations as relatable to feeling if
that feeling is still not resisting
right there so it's very real
it's just on a different level of that
generality where you're looking so by
focusing on the part you are the only
one that loses the sight of the general
context general image the phenomenon but
it doesn't mean that the farm the
phenomena disappears because you don't
see it anymore it's still there which is
why you can keep looking at the part and
not like ask yourself wait a minute what
is this now you know exactly what part
you're looking of which means the
context is still at the peripheral of
your mind but you've been negating to
look in the peripheral and only focusing
on what's in front of you actually
focusing on that making a point of just
staring at that that for you you assume
that this peripheral that is there
doesn't exist anymore that moment in the
other talk I said for most people even
their own thoughts feel like they're not
real they're not concrete enough because
they got used to only the concrete
palpable aspects of their experience to
be the reality but if the thoughts were
not real how can you think that how can
you talk about how can you remember
things you thought it's real whatever
that's not good I didn't say whatever
only material things are real or real or
ornamental things he said whatever has
the nature of manifestation that's why
it's real and that's exactly what a sort
of body begins understanding that that's
where impermanence is oh whatever has
the nature of manifestation whatever can
manifest whatever can appear
it cannot be mind that's what it means
whatever has the need that usual
translation whatever is the nature of
arising has the nature of ceasing
whatever is of nature to manifest that's
why it's impermanent
because he has a nature of manifestation
on its own not a nature of manifestation
being created by me or coming from me
and that's how you will force yourself
to uproot the gratuitous ownership of
various manifestations not through
denying them not to try to destroy them
but by seeing that you can't own the
even if you want to once you start
uprooting the ownership no sense of self
can remain that maintained fueled by
that ownership and then any view that
you had that it's me therefore things
are mine will fade and it will become
inconceivable so it doesn't matter
whether you wish to be free from sense
of self in the view of self if you stop
me Danny in the sense of ownership
through ride reflection you will be free
from the sense of self that's why the
Buddha meant when he said it's like even
if I chicken if even if a hen sits on
her eggs doesn't know if it sits on the
eggs but even if she doesn't wish may my
chick Spears the shell and come out
safely they will cuz she sits on them
what if a hen
even if she wishes that her chicks
pierce out safely but she doesn't sit on
her eggs they want so even if you wish
may I be free from sense of self and
become an utter hunt if you're not doing
it right now on the level of removing
the ownership you won't be free from
those things even if you don't wish to
be free from sense of self and wish to
become another hunt you will if you
start removing the ownership when a kind
of understanding the independence of
manifestation assumptions well it will
then remove the assumption assumption is
maintained through ignoring the basis of
assumption so the assumption of sense of
self sense of I am is maintained through
ignoring the fact that you are not the
owner of things so then your act but so
that that's how the assumption becomes
kind of its own fuel it fuels you
ignoring but it's the very presence of
ignoring the fuel back the assumption so
it's a vicious circle throwing through
that's where you can't break away from
it accidentally or spontaneously or or
or or in a split of a second you can
only break away by understanding it and
then forcing yourself to go the other
way now everything is for me but I'm
told I should not regard it as mind and
you have faith in what you were told and
you keep doing it because it corresponds
that things are actually no blows that's
how you get to see because you stop
fueling the assumption and after a while
when that views of those are some
have faded then you get to recognize
what has faded like what the Buddha said
like a carpet they're using the X he
doesn't think Oh today I'm wearing my
handle thin this much tomorrow I will do
this much no he just keeps doing it and
doing it and doing it until one day he
looks at the handle oh I must replace it
because it's completely gone
that's how assumptions fall off not like
I'm grasping I refuse to grasp thus I'm
free from the super Donna you can only
wish that as that is